taxactonline.com 2008-05-09

# TaxACT Online Truste Privacy Policy Statement

**www.taxactonline.com** is the web site of **2nd Story Software, Inc.**

Our postal address is  
 **5925 Dry Creek Lane NE  
Cedar Rapids, IA 52402**

We can be reached via e-mail at customerservice@taxact.com  
Or you can reach us by telephone at 319-373-3600  
Or you can reach us by fax at 319-447-4674

[](http://www.truste.org/ivalidate.php?url=www.taxactonline.com&sealid=101)We, at 2nd Story Software, respect your privacy and the confidentiality of your personal information (including email address). Our company's resources and entire staff are fully committed to safeguarding your personal data (including email address) by ensuring that the highest security and other precautionary measures are in place to protect your non-public information. That is why we do not share your information (including email address) with third parties, affiliates, or partners except as outlined in this privacy statement. We only collect, store and use your personal information (including email address) for defined purposes. The purposes include preparing and filing your tax return, supplying service and support, and notifying you of updates, new products, and services.

2nd Story Software is committed to protecting your privacy and data. At any time, you may contact 2nd Story Software to request what information you have given us and request correction or deletion. Our goal is to ensure the highest levels of security and confidentiality. Please note, your tax return data is not available to anyone in the support center and therefore cannot be reviewed, changed, or deleted by support personnel.

## Participant of TRUSTe Privacy Program

2nd Story Software, Inc. is a certified licensee of the TRUSTe Privacy Seal Program. TRUSTe is an independent, non-profit organization whose mission is to enable individuals and organizations to establish trusting relationships based on respect for personal identity and information (including email address) by promoting the use of fair information practices. This privacy statement covers the site www.taxactonline.com. Because the owner of this Web site wants to demonstrate its commitment to our users' privacy, 2nd Story Software has agreed to disclose its information practices and have its privacy practices reviewed for compliance by TRUSTe.

If you have questions or concerns regarding this statement, you should first contact 2nd Story Software, Inc.'s Customer Service department by one of the following methods, which have been listed at the top of this page. If you do not receive acknowledgment of your inquiry or your inquiry is not satisfactorily addressed, you should then contact TRUSTe through the TRUSTe Watchdog Dispute Resolution Process <http://www.truste.org/consumers/watchdog_complaint.php> TRUSTe will serve as a liaison between you and 2nd Story Software, Inc.

The TRUSTe program covers only information that is collected through this Web site, and does not cover information that may be collected through software downloaded from the site.

## Information Collected

2nd Story Software will only collect, store, use, and share your personal information (including email address) as it is defined by TaxACTOnline.com's privacy statement and as regulated by state and federal laws. We require personal information such as your email address and full name to register as a member with www.taxactonline.com. We need to obtain your social security number and date of birth to confirm your identity and file your taxes. We also require other sensitive information such as your credit card information to process your order.

When filing a tax return online, in addition to entering your own personal information, you may be asked to enter personal information of those who are either a joint filer or dependants in the same household. Information collected on the TaxACTonline.com website is stored by 2nd Story Software and, unless it is otherwise stated, is used to prepare and electronically file users tax returns, as well as notify you when new/enhanced products and services become available. We do not disclose user's information (including email address) to third parties except when the user requests to e-file their return. In just case, we will disclose information to the appropriate government officials and financial institutions. We only communicate with users when necessary, such as issues with the user's tax return or to provide requested services.

If you choose to use our referral service to tell a friend about our site, we will ask you for your friend's name and email address. We will automatically send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the site. 2nd Story Software stores this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email and tracking the success of our referral program.

Your friend may contact us at refer@taxact.com to request that we remove this information from our database.

Only information you have given us (including email address) is stored by us. We do not supplement your information with information from other companies.

If you do not want to receive promotional e-mail from us in the future, please let us know by sending an email to us at the above address or calling us at the above telephone number or writing to us at the above address and telling us that you do not want to receive e-mail from our company.

Some information, including name and email address is shared with www.taxact.com also owned by 2nd Story Software, Inc. for purposes of notifying you of the release of the next year's online program and potentially other products of interest. If you prefer not to be notified of next year's release or to receive any product information from TaxACT, please contact us via email, phone, fax, or mail to make your request to be removed from our email list. Please refer to the [Taxact.com privacy policy](http://www.taxact.com/privacy_policy.asp).

You also have the ability to post a testimonial on the website as public information. Personal information is required in order to post these testimonials. Personal information such as your name and email address is collected at the webpage. The webpage default is to keep your personal information private however you will have the ability to opt-in to post your personal information publicly.

## Clear Gifs (Web Beacons/Web Bugs)

We use clear gifs in our HTML-based emails to let us know the number of emails that have been opened by recipients. This allows us to gauge the effectiveness of certain communications and the effectiveness of our marketing campaigns. **We do not tie the information gathered by clear gifs to our customers' personally identifiable information** (including email address). If you would like to opt-out of these emails, please see "Changing and Deleting Personal Information."

## Changing and Deleting information

With regard to tax return information, the user has the option of either mailing or e-filing their tax returns. If the user decides to e-file their tax return, the user will not be able to update their personal information once their tax return has been filed, unless the IRS rejects their return. Users may check if their return has been accepted or rejected by accessing [Check e-File Status](https://www.taxact.com/secure_ef/efstatus.asp).

In addition, on October 15 of each year, the IRS no longer accepts e-filed returns. On that date, all tax returns are archived and the TaxACT Online system is taken down for re-tooling. The prior year's archived returns are only accessible by the system for importing purposes only and user changes can no longer be made to a tax return after October 15th of the tax filing year.

**If you do not want to receive promotional e-mail from us in the future, please let us know by using one of the contact methods listed at the top of this page. Please make sure you supply the same e-mail address to us that you are receiving the e-mail from. In some cases, e-mail addresses are being forwarded by your ISP to another e-mail address. We must have the one that is listed in the e-mail you receive from us. In addition, users may unsubscribe by replying to the opt-out instructions at the bottom of each email they receive.**

## Security Measures

Our primary concern is that your tax return and other personal information (including email address) is private and secure. At 2nd Story Software we use the industry-standard Secure Socket Layers (SSL) protocol which provides data encryption, message integrity, and server authentication when your data is sent to us. When you see a small lock in the bottom right or left corner of your browser window, you know your data is being encrypted for transmission.

All information (including email address) you enter while using TaxACT Online is used strictly by 2nd Story Software, Inc. to provide the services requested by our customers. We maintain physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards to protect your personal information (including email address). All data is stored on 2nd Story Software servers and is backed up to prevent the loss of data. Electronically filed returns, which are further encrypted, are sent directly from 2nd Story Software to the IRS via a secure connection. Access to (and the use thereof) personally identifiable customer information (including email address) is restricted to authorized personnel and is permitted only when prompted by you, or as dictated by service, support, and/or fulfillment requirements. **2nd Story Software, Inc. will not sell or rent your name or other personal information (including email address) to any third party in ways other than disclosed in this privacy statement. Personally identifiable information (including email address) is only shared with third party intermediaries providing they have been contracted to act on 2nd Story Software's behalf or to carry out a specific function. Under these circumstances, third party intermediaries may not sell or transfer this information nor may they use information for any secondary purpose.**

## Third Party Intermediaries

We use an outside credit card processing company to bill users for goods and services. This company does not retain, share, store, or use personally identifiable information (including email address) for any secondary purposes.

We use an email delivery and marketing company to send emails that you have agreed to receive. Pixel tags and cookies are used in those email messages and at our website to help us measure the effectiveness of our advertising and how visitors use our site. For more information about the technology used to deliver our emails, or how to set your browser to reject cookies, please [click here](http://www.doubleclick.com/us/about_doubleclick/privacy/).

We may use advertising companies to serve advertisements for us on our website. These companies may employ cookies and action tags (also known as single pixel gifs or web beacons) to measure advertising effectiveness. Any information that these third parties collect via cookies and action tags is completely anonymous. If you would like more information about this practice and your choices, click here (<http://www.networkadvertising.org/optout_nonppii.asp>) and here (<http://www.advertising.com/Privacy.html>) We do not share, rent or sell any personally identifiable information to these companies.

On occasion, we will enter into a written contract with third party intermediary companies to help us to complete a business process, service, or function on our behalf. Without limitation, third party intermediaries may specialize in providing services such as: consulting or contracted development and maintenance, temporary workers, data processing, as well as direct and network marketing. These third party intermediaries may not use or retain personally identifiable (including email address) information for any secondary purpose. Additionally, they may not divulge, rent, or sell any information (including email address) that may be gained through their relationship with 2nd Story Software.

2nd Story Software may also enter into marketing alliances and joint marketing relationships. 2nd Story Software's relationship with these companies shall not represent our endorsement for the products or services these companies offer; and, are only being made available within TaxACTOnline.com to serve as added conveniences for our site's visitors. Unless you have supplied your consent, 2nd Story Software does not share your name and other personally identifiable information (including email address); and, 2nd Story Software shall never sell or rent any information (including email address) that identifies you personally or individually . Otherwise, for a third party intermediary to obtain your contact information or personal data (including email address), you, yourself, will need to supply them with your information or become their direct customer.

Written agreements are established between 2nd Story Software and all third party intermediaries, as well as joint marketing and alliance companies. Each agreement strictly limits the use of your personally identifiable information (including email address) to the scope of the contract. Contractual agreements, such as these, also stipulate safeguard, handling, and other precautionary care procedures, which are required to be taken. The contractual agreements we have in place and/or establish also govern confidentiality rights by limiting the information that we can share to include only aggregated statistical data.

## Links to Other Web Sites

TaxactOnline.com may contain links to third-party Web sites. Each of these links shall be clearly identified. 2nd Story Software does not direct or oversee the policies, procedures, or other practices for companies other than 2nd Story. 2nd Story Software does not endorse the products and services that are offered by third party companies. The presence of third party links within TaxACTOnline.com are for convenience purposes only and should not be considered as representing an endorsement by 2nd Story. Some of these third party sites may collect information about you or request sensitive, personal information from you. If accessing a third party site via a link, which originated from TaxACTOnline.com, you will be subject to the policies and procedures that have been established by the third party. We encourage you to review their privacy policies to learn more about what information is collected, how it is used, and how it is stored.

2nd Story Software may provide third parties with links to TaxACTOnline.com. Once you have been redirected to a TaxACTOnline.com web page, the terms and conditions of our site shall apply.

## Notices and Service Alerts

Although we respect and honor your privacy preferences, 2nd Story Software shall maintain and reserve the right to contact you (via email, phone, fax, mail, or otherwise) when it deems appropriate, such as for nonmarketing purposes (such as bug alerts, security breaches, and/or changes that may impact your ability to use TaxACT products and services). In certain circumstances, we may use our website, newspapers, or other public means to post a notice.

## Service, Support and Suggestions Section of TaxACT.com

2nd Story Software offers technical support and customer service on the TaxACT products line to our customers through its sister site, TaxACT.com. You may choose to submit a question through the service and support section of the TaxACT.com web site or contact our support staff directly. The information submitted via the service and support section (including email address) is not stored or shared with third parties, affiliates, alliance, or joint marketing companies, or any other third party intermediaries. It is used to research your problem, provide answers, and/or request more information. If you make a suggestion using the service and support section of our web site, the suggestion alone may be stored, but no personal data (including email address) will be stored with the suggestion. 2nd Story Software, Inc. does retain the right to use your suggestions and product enhancement ideas to improve the TaxACT web sites and product line without obligation to you.

For each visitor to our Web page, our Web server automatically recognizes only the consumer's domain name. For each visitor to our Web page, our Web server automatically recognizes only the consumer's domain name, IP address, access times, and pages viewed. IP addresses, etc. are not linked to personally identifiable information (including email address).

## Use of Log Files, LiveStats and Cookies

Like most Web servers, 2nd Story Software relies on log files. Log files include: Internet Protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, Internet Service Provider (ISP), number of page views, platform type, date and time stamps, as well as the number visitors to our web site. This information is used by 2nd Story Software to administer the site, analyze trends, track aggregated user movements, and gather broad demographic information for aggregated use only. Our Web site also uses tracking software, which is supplied by LiveStats, by DeepMetrix. This software further enables us to anonymously analyze trends occurring on our Web site. Personally identifiable information (including email address) is not stored by the LiveStats server, as the software does not collect personal information such as name, age, phone number, mailing address, email address, or credit card numbers from visitors. For more information about the LiveStats Log Analyzer Software and DeepMetrix's commitment to privacy for the companies who use LiveStats, visit <http://www.deepmetrix.com/legal/privacy/products/> For each visitor to our Web page, LiveStats automatically recognizes only the consumer's domain name, IP address, access times and pages viewed. IP addresses, etc. are not linked to personally identifiable information (including email address).

TaxACTOnline.com employs the use of cookies. A cookie is a piece of data stored on the user's computer tied to information about the user. Usage of a cookie is in no way linked to any personally identifiable information (including email address) while on our site. We use both session ID cookies and persistent cookies. For the session ID cookie, once users close the browser, the cookie simply terminates. A persistent cookie is a small text file stored on the user's hard drive for an extended period of time. If users reject the cookie, they will not be able to prepare their tax return using TaxActOnline.com.

## General Disclosure of Aggregated Information

2nd Story Software may disclose aggregate information to the IRS or other parties, however, may not represent any information, which may be used to identify you personally or individually without your expressed consent (including email address). Examples may include, but are not limited to: the total number of users served by a TaxACT product/service, general age group ratios, and other statistical data relating to tax preparation and electronic filing service.

## Changes to our Privacy Policy

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, the homepage, and other places we deem appropriate so our users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it.

If, however, we are going to use users' personally identifiable information (including email address) in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection we will notify users by posting a prominent notice on our Web site for 30 days.

If we merge with, or are acquired by another company, the resulting combined company will use the Personal Information you have provided as described in this policy. If we cease operation, your Personal Information may be transferred to and used by another company that offers similar or related products or services. You will be notified via prominent notice on our Web site for 30 days of any such change in ownership or control of your personal information.

## Disclaimer

Though we make every effort to preserve user privacy, we may need to disclose personal information (including email address) when required by law wherein we have a good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with a current judicial proceeding, a court order, or legal process served on our Web site.
